<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Josh Kerr</title>
  <link href="http://joshkerr.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joshkerr.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-20T09:38:33-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://joshkerr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Josh Kerr</name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>My TV spot on PBS</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/my-tv-spot-on-pbs/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T08:23:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/my-tv-spot-on-pbs</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/1nR_TZDeIGs?fs=1&amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was featured in a new TV show on PBS about entreprenuers in Austin.  The show filmed this past summer and just aired in November.  Hopefully PBS will pick up the series, it would be a great platform to highlight the wonderful companies people are starting here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textmate 2 Alpha is great</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/textmate-2-alpha-is-great/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T07:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/textmate-2-alpha-is-great</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of Textmate, I&amp;#8217;ve been using it as my goto Mac code/text editor for more than a few years.  Over that time, the app has remained exactly the same.  The developer would fix bugs every now and then, but the app itself did not progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New editors would popup every now and then, but Textmate continued to be the best of breed.  This was partly because it was extensible and the developer community was thriving.  So I continued to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago the developer blogged about working on a version 2 of the app.  No details on when or what the version 2 would be and for another year we saw no major release.  Then a few months ago the developer posted a teaser screenshot.  This month we received our first version 2 Alpha copy.  Finally, after years of waiting there is a significatly new version of Textmate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/_config.yml.png&quot; alt=&quot;Textmate 2 Alpha&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version feels modern.  It has a modern clean interface, very similar to the 1.0 version, but with polish and UI tweaks that make it feel pretty slick.  It doesn&amp;#8217;t get in the way of what makes Textmate so great, the ability to edit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an editor, version 2 is just plain awesome.  Multiple carets, the ability to create multiple selections in a single view is really useful.  Its basically a discontinuous selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/photos/2011-12-20-textmate-2-alpha-is-great.markdown.png&quot; alt=&quot;Multiple carets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really cool feature is the project drawer which is found on most editors, but for some reason wasn&amp;#8217;t included in 1.0.  With 2.0, the drawer now only shows files and folders, but updates status on SCM, can execute commands, supports smart folders and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://macromates.com/changes&quot;&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt; can be found on the Textmate site.  You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; Textmate 2.0 alpha from the Macromates website.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Clear water in Northwest Montana</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/clear-water-in-northwest-montana/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T07:35:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/clear-water-in-northwest-montana</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;2QOJX.jpg&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/2QOJX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2QOJX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tell it is deep by the shadow.  That is some clear water you got there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>YouTube hits 1,000,000,000,000 playbacks in 2011</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/youtube-hits-1-trillion-views/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/youtube-hits-1-trillion-views</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/neowin-main/~3/7vxboQ7f8hM/youtube-hits-1000000000000-playbacks-in-2011&quot;&gt;YouTube hits 1,000,000,000,000 playbacks in 2011&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.neowin.net/images/news/logos/1569810845yt_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
That big number you see above is 1 trillion and YouTube just crossed that number in total playbacks for 2011. The site also posted up the top videos for 2011 based on views. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neowin.net/news/youtube-hits-1000000000000-playbacks-in-2011&quot;&gt;Read more&amp;#8230;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neowin.net/&quot;&gt;Neowin.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Very cool Facebook timelines</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/people-customized-cool-facebook-timelines/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/12/20/people-customized-cool-facebook-timelines</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;5wAJo.jpg&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/5wAJo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;5wAJo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some people are pretty creative with their Facebook timelines.  Here are some great &lt;a href=&quot;http://savedelete.com/get-started-most-innovative-facebook-timeline-cover.html&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of what you can do with yours.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sweet photo of a sleeping dog</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/11/13/3963682950/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/11/13/3963682950</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bXdn9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Google Reader and Mac/iOS RSS readers that sync</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/25/greader-sync/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/25/greader-sync</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2011/10/24/google_reader_and_mac_ios_rss_readers_th&quot;&gt;Google Reader and Mac/iOS RSS readers that sync&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2011/10/upcoming-changes-to-reader-new-look-new.html&quot;&gt;announcement of changes coming for Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; worries me some. Though I don’t use Google Reader directly, I — like many iPhone, iPad, and Mac users — use RSS readers that sync via Google Reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This announcement isn’t just a reminder of the fragility of the system: it removes some features that people use. Google Reader’s social and sharing features are going away in favor of integration with Google+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes sense from Google’s point of view — a single, Google-wide social network should be better than a separate network for each Google app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, there are users who will miss the current, about-to-disappear features. (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://nick.typepad.com/blog/2011/10/what-the-upcoming-google-reader-changes-mean-for-feeddemon.html&quot;&gt;What the Upcoming Google Reader Changes Mean for FeedDemon&lt;/a&gt; for an example of how one RSS reader will have to change.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say that the system is fragile, I don’t mean that Google Reader itself is fragile. I mean that using it as a syncing system for other apps is fragile. There are a couple things that RSS reader developers know, that the average RSS reader user probably doesn’t know, which will make this more apparent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Reader API is undocumented, unsupported, and unofficial. This is unlike &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/apis/maps/&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; and others which do have documented and official APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the API is not official, there is no commitment to keeping it working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though RSS reader developers have received much-appreciated unofficial support from Google, that’s not the same as building a feature on solid ground. Smart developers are rightly uncomfortable relying on undocumented, unofficial, unsupported APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, because syncing is so important for so many RSS reader users, developers have had to gamble. With syncing part of the definition of a minimum viable RSS reader, and with Google Reader the only option for syncing, the choice to use Google Reader is more necessity than choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Questions about the future&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gamble has paid off so far, with the exception of the features about to be replaced. It’s been an especially good thing for RSS reader users, who can mix-and-match clients on different platforms, who can move with relative ease between one client and another. (The situation is similar to Twitter clients: users are not stuck with one client from one particular developer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I remain optimistic about the future of Google Reader and apps that sync via Google Reader, there are a few reasons for concern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Google Reader is a mature app, its lack of an official, documented, supported API sends a message, intended or not, about its importance to Google. And Google has cut apps before, even high-profile apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlewave.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Google Wave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FeedDemon author &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/fougrapi/browse_thread/thread/b0eb7f67939c627&quot;&gt;Nick Bradbury asked&lt;/a&gt; on the unofficial API support list if Google Reader is being retired. At this writing, a couple days after the recent announcement, the question remains unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/search/googlereader&quot;&gt;#googlereader&lt;/a&gt; and @googlereader traffic on Twitter since the announcement, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/googlereader&quot;&gt;@googlereader&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account has been silent. (At this writing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wording of the recent Google Reader announcement emphasized how users could export their data. While that’s a good thing — being able to move one’s data is important — the emphasis made it seem like a request or a warning. That characterization is mine, yes, but it’s shared by other developers (not just RSS reader developers) that have read that announcement. This may not have been the author’s intention: it’s possible the author was being careful and doing the right thing by mentioning data exporting. But it didn’t read that way, at least to some developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t know what the value of Google Reader is to Google. It doesn’t appear to have ads a la search or Gmail, though ads do appear in feeds via Google’s AdSense for feeds, and that presumably makes money. Does Google Reader feed the search engine ranking system? Does it exist to help ensure the goodwill of influential writers who use Google Reader? I can speculate, but I don’t know, which is my point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, I remain optimistic, because I don’t have any solid reason to expect things to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Google Reader &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; just changed, and some syncing RSS readers will lose some features, and I take that as a reminder that it could change in a way that breaks syncing, and Google would not have broken any official APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not an RSS reader developer any more. But if I were, I’d start looking for an alternative syncing system right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/&quot;&gt;inessential.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Canon EOS-1D X first hands-on (video)</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/25/eos-1dx-handson/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/25/eos-1dx-handson</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2011/10/25/canon-eos-1d-x-hands-on-video/&quot;&gt;Canon EOS-1D X first hands-on (video)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2011/10/25/canon-eos-1d-x-hands-on-video/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2011/10/2011-10-25-img1503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Professional photographers know the drill: every few years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/tag/Canon/&quot;&gt;Canon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/tag/Nikon/&quot;&gt;Nikon&lt;/a&gt; announces a game-changing DSLR, often prompting top photogs to unload their complete kits and switch to another system in a never-ending attempt to shoot with the best. This time, Canon is first out of the gate, with its flagship EOS-1D X &amp;#8211; the latest in a series that dates back to 2001 with the EOS-1D. As you&amp;#8217;ve probably noticed, the company&amp;#8217;s new top model looks virtually identical to its decade-old ancestor, but is otherwise a far cry from that four megapixel CCD sensor-sporting dinosaur. We&amp;#8217;ve been anxiously awaiting an opportunity to check out Canon&amp;#8217;s new $6,800 18.1 megapixel full-frame model since first getting word of the beastly camera &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2011/10/18/canon-announces-eos-1d-x-full-frame-18mp-sensor-14-fps-204-80/&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, and just had a chance to go hands-on during the company&amp;#8217;s Pro Solutions event in London. Jump past the break for our impressions and a video walkthrough.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com&quot;&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Trick shot basketball frisbee competition</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/trick-shot/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/trick-shot</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/W_2eU1ykV3k?fs=1&amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Great trick shot competition.  Is there computer generated effects going on here or are these guys really that good?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Star Wars meets Pulp Fiction</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/star-wars-meets-pulp-fiction/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/star-wars-meets-pulp-fiction</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/rajCyWb9BFA?fs=1&amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sick rendition of Zeppelin by Michael Winslow</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/sick-zeppelin-rendition/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/sick-zeppelin-rendition</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/QxcCC2g1Ke0?fs=1&amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing rendition of Whole Lotta Love by Michael Winslow on a talk show from Norway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Japanese girl explains Star Wars</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/japanese-girl-explains-starwars/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/22/japanese-girl-explains-starwars</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/-eCSHJINqCo?fs=1&amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MarkdownPad editor for Windows</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/21/3957640176/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/21/3957640176</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally there is a decent Markdown editor for Windows.&amp;nbsp; Called MarkdownPad it has a dual pane view with source on the left and preview on the right.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/yOAkB.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can download it &lt;a href=&quot;http://markdownpad.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Android Face Login</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/19/3957130797/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/19/3957130797</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;background-image: none; border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/image_thumb.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;272&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What were the developers at Google thinking when they came up with a Face login feature?&amp;nbsp; Not only didn’t this feature work properly when Google demoed it at their big reveal for Ice Cream Sandwich the new Android OS, but it doesn’t solve a customer pain.&amp;nbsp; Why would you devote time on stage to showing off something like this?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are so many problems with this technology.&amp;nbsp; First, the phones don’t have a fast enough processor to make the recognition even remotely useful.&amp;nbsp; It takes several seconds to properly align and then a few more to do the actual recognition.&amp;nbsp; By then I’d already have typed my password and been well into doing something productive on my phone.&amp;nbsp; This feature is simply a party gag, something to show off to those who have more useful iPhones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google is trying so hard to differentiate their product from the iOS products that they are forcing innovations that aren’t at all appealing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jekyll bootstrap</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/17/3956638173/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/17/3956638173</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;background-image: none; border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/image_thumb.png&quot; width=&quot;504&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A great GUI toolkit for bootstrapping your website designed by the guys who built Twitter.&amp;nbsp; It has almost every possible GUI element that you could want and formatted to support a wide variety of browser types.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This github project is for the Jekyll version of that toolkit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nhoss2.github.com/jekyll-bootstrap&quot;&gt;Jekyll bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Learn How to make Angry Birds (co.uk)</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/16/how-to-make-angry-birds/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/16/how-to-make-angry-birds</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is really cool:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the game I’m going to be making is to be based on the extremely popular Angry Birds by Rovio, a AAA title &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.develop-online.net/news/37242/Angry-Birds-cost-Rovio-100k-has-made-50m&quot;&gt;which cost some $140k USD to make&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/screenShot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;screenShot&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/screenShot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, since its just me making this I will have to take a few short-cuts and will be concentrating on the core part of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cloning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I start I should mention that I do not condone the cloning of games in any way; what I’m doing in these tutorials is purely for educational purposes and I have no plans to release the game at the end of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, lets have a look at the requirements for a bare-bones version of the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background, mid-ground and foreground layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird characters,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pig characters,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slingshot,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rigid body pieces – materials: wood, stone, glass in rectangle, square and triangle shapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collision detection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possible requirement for advanced broad-phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various static and dynamic shapes – rectangles, triangles, circles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object colliding call-back system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very stable physics engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated object sleeping system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some kind of editor to allow layout of levels and creation of graphics. I’m using Flash CS4 for all this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I’m going to tackle from that list is to get the world set up so that there is a nice looking environment and to root the project in something solid looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with the podium that the birds gets launched from; its going to be a static object in the physics system and to keep things simple I’m going to compose all objects from primitive parts, so collision wise at least the podium will be made from some squares and triangles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podium.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;podium&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podium.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;224&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it’s covered with a repeating earth texture, so the first thing is to make this. Its actually quite easy to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/repeatingEarth.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;repeatingEarth&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/repeatingEarth.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part is easy, just pick two vaguely earthy colours and paint one half of the texture in each colour, with a nice rough overlap in the midddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, offset the image by half the width and height (I used photoshop’s offset filter) to get the image in the middle. Then you can rough up the middle edge as you did in the first image. Once you’re done you’ll have a nice infinitely repeatable texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to actually apply this texture to an arbitrary object in Flash, you import the image onto the stage, then right click and and choose ‘Break apart’. Then you can use the eye-dropper tool to pick that texture as a fill texture which you can then apply to any shape with the paint bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/repeatDemo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;repeatDemo&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/repeatDemo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;153&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infinite repeats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we’re making all collision objects from primitive shapes, we need to decide what basic shapes we’re going to be using. I chose these for the podium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podiumShapes.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;podiumShapes&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podiumShapes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;179&quot; height=&quot;68&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podium shapes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can be rotated, duplicated and placed to form the podium shape:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podiumShapesComposed.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;podiumShapesComposed&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/podiumShapesComposed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;242&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podium composed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when actually creating the shape for the visible part of the podium, its important to follow the exact same shape that you could compose only using the primitive collision shapes in various different configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will start to become very useful later when we try to integrate the physics system with the graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Foreground&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foreground consists of another tiling shape; the soil. This was made from a rectangle, and lots of ovals in Flash, just repeated and placed. Its important to make sure it tiles so pay attention at the edges and use grid snap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/foreground.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;foreground&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/foreground.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;224&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mid-ground&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another tiling shape, this time rolling hills with a few far off plants; nothing out of the ordinary here, just make sure it tiles. You’ll want to make this one wider than the screen – I made mine roughly twice as wide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/midground.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;midground&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/midground-300x50.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mid-ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you guessed it, tiling shapes again – this one is roughly one screen in size:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/background.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;background&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/background-300x217.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these layers have been set to export for action-script in the Flash IDE; I’ve appended every name with &lt;em&gt;Fla &lt;/em&gt;so that I can tell in code which classes are from Flash and which are my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything should now be exported as a .swc which you can enable in File-&amp;gt;Publish Settings-&amp;gt;Flash-&amp;gt;Export SWC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can import this SWC into your project in your favourite flash code compiler; I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sapphiresteel.com/Products/amethyst-ide/article/amethyst-product-page&quot;&gt;Amythyst&lt;/a&gt; because I cannot live without Visual Studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Putting it together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the idea with all these separate layers is that the code will place and animate them separately to give a parallax effect as the camera pans/zooms around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked a screen size of 640×360 (wide-screen), and a world size of 2560×720 (four screens wide by two screens high). And I’ve centred the world at 0,0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a good camera class is fundamental to any game, particularly this one which requires lots of smooth pans and zooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least it should provide functions for converting coordinates between world space and screen space and visa versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there are three layers of parallax at work, the camera needs to be able to position each one as it pans around the scene, so its constructor takes them as parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Camera&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;, midground:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;, foreground:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;, bird:Bird&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&#8230;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bird parameter is just a dummy at the moment which represents the focal point for the camera – it contains accessors for position so the camera can know where in the world it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get the camera to centre on the bird no matter where the bird is on screen we need to do a little bit of maths; forming what is known as the &lt;em&gt;world to screen&lt;/em&gt; matrix, so called because it transforms points in world space into screen space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; Update&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; dt:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    m_worldToScreen = &lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Matrix&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    m_worldToScreen.&lt;span&gt;translate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; -m_bird.&lt;span&gt;m_Pos&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;, -m_bird.&lt;span&gt;m_Pos&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    m_worldToScreen.&lt;span&gt;scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; m_scale.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;, m_scale.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    m_worldToScreen.&lt;span&gt;translate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; Constants.&lt;span&gt;kScreenDimensions&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;, Constants.&lt;span&gt;kScreenDimensions&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    m_foreground.&lt;span&gt;transform&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;matrix&lt;/span&gt; = m_worldToScreen;
 
    &lt;span&gt;// for screen-&amp;gt;world matrix&lt;/span&gt;
    m_screenToWorld = m_worldToScreen.&lt;span&gt;clone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    m_screenToWorld.&lt;span&gt;invert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in the above function is: first the camera is centred on the bird, then any zoom is applied and finally we add on the centre of the screen to make sure the bird is in the centre (remember, 0,0 is the top left of the screen, not the centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then take this matrix and apply it as the transform for the foreground geometry, so in actual fact &lt;strong&gt;the geometry moves around the camera&lt;/strong&gt;, not the other way around – which is a bit difficult to get your head around at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first translate in the above snippet is easier to understand with this in mind – 0,0 is the destination for the world geometry, coming from the position of the bird and &lt;em&gt;0-m_bird.m_Pos&lt;/em&gt; is the vector which achieves that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I take a copy of this matrix and invert it so that I can do the opposite transform whenever I need to convert a point in screen-space to world-space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the parallax effect on the back and mid-ground layers, I do a similar piece of maths for each layer (each layer getting its own world-&amp;gt;screen matrix), the only change is that I divide the x translation by the layer’s z-depth, which causes them to move at different speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this will work fine, but it won’t prevent the camera from leaving the bounds of the world. In order to do that we need to understand the camera’s relationship with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, lets take a look at the world, the camera and their relationship:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/figure1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;figure1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/figure1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;585&quot; height=&quot;201&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1&lt;/em&gt; shows the entire extents of the world and also one possible location for the camera. Note that the camera has the dimensions of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this configuration, the camera is actually showing a view which is partially outside the world, which should not be allowed to happen. In order to fix this problem we need to know exactly how far outside the camera is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/figure2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;figure2&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wildbunny.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/figure2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;586&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows the measurements we need to correct this problem (the red arrows) and also shows in green, the camera’s position after it has been corrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; Update&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; dt:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;// clamp camera to only show map&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; translate:Vector2 = m_bird.&lt;span&gt;m_Pos&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_Neg&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; screenHalfExtents:Vector2 = &lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Vector2&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Constants.&lt;span&gt;kScreenDimensions&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;, Constants.&lt;span&gt;kScreenDimensions&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;Div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Vector2&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;m_scale.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;, m_scale.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; mapExtents:Vector2 = Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;MulScalar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; topLeft:Vector2 = m_bird.&lt;span&gt;m_Pos&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;Sub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;screenHalfExtents&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; bottomRight:Vector2 = m_bird.&lt;span&gt;m_Pos&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;Add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;screenHalfExtents&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; correctLeft:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;Math&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;topLeft.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;+Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; correctTop:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;Math&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;topLeft.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;+Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; correctRight:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;Math&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;-bottomRight.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; correctBottom:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;Math&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;-bottomRight.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    translate.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt; += correctLeft - correctRight;
    translate.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt; += correctTop - correctBottom;
 
        &#8230;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is the code which calculates the red arrowed regions shown in Figure 2, and applies any corrections needed to the initial translation of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one caveat to watch out for: the foreground layer is a child of the main MovieClip which makes up the game – this is essential because otherwise the camera would only be translating the foreground shape and not everything in the world, which would be all bad. However, because the camera is translating the main MovieClip, the mid and background layers cannot be children of it. Instead, they must be children of the &lt;strong&gt;stage&lt;/strong&gt;; this allows them to be translated independently to give the correct effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a tile strip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is relatively simple, you just divide the width of the world by the width of a tile to get the number of repetitions, set the starting point and then just instance the correct MovieClip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; CreateTileStrip&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;:Vector2, &lt;span&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span&gt;Class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; obj:&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; mc:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; obj &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; tileRoot:&lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; worldWidth:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = Constants.&lt;span&gt;kWorldAabb&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_HalfExtents&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; numTiles:&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;worldWidth&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;mc.&lt;span&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; + &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;;
 
    &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; i:&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;; i&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;numTiles; i++&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; x:&lt;span&gt;Number&lt;/span&gt; = i&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;mc.&lt;span&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
        mc.&lt;span&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; = x + &lt;span&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_x&lt;/span&gt;;
        mc.&lt;span&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;m_y&lt;/span&gt;-mc.&lt;span&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;;
 
        tileRoot.&lt;span&gt;addChild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; mc &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
 
        obj = &lt;span&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
        mc = &lt;span&gt;MovieClip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; obj &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; tileRoot;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you call it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;m_backgroundLayer = CreateTileStrip&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; bottomLeft, BackgroundTileFla &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
m_midgroundLayer = CreateTileStrip&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; bottomLeft, MidgroundTileFla &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
m_foregroundLayer = CreateTileStrip&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; bottomLeft, ForegroundTileFla &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually pleasantly surprised how easy it was to pass a class as a type in actionscript, much easier than in c# or c++ and it really makes it simple to tile any shape that you export from the Flash IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First thoughts on Siri</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/15/first-thoughts-on-siri/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/15/first-thoughts-on-siri</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/siri.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;&quot; title=&quot;siri&quot; src=&quot;http://joshkerr.s3.amazonaws.com/images/siri_thumb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;siri&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 4S is super fast, runs iOS 5 which is chock full of goodness and comes with Siri which is arguably the best thing about it.  It is marketed as a personal assistant in your pocket.  For me, Siri is the Austin startup that was purchased last year and had an app in the App Store that had some potential but did not live up to its billing.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After spending a day with Siri on the iPhone 4S I’m walking away with a completely different view.  Siri really is a personal assistant in your pocket.  You talk to it as if you were dictating instructions to a person.  It amazingly has the ability to recognize keywords and translate them into actual tasks.  It works great and opens the door to a whole new category of computing driven by voice.  Apple has integrated Siri into its own apps, but it remains unclear if they plan to enable an API to allow third party developers to tap into its power.  If they know what is good for them, they will.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Faceshift</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/08/faceshift/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/08/faceshift</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;IWjTF.gif&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IWjTF.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;IWjTF.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Doggy AT-AT</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/08/doggy-atat/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/08/doggy-atat</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/WNt3ZxJsiKI/doggy-at-at.html&quot;&gt;Doggy AT-AT&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://craphound.com/images/307674_245628275488785_162077150510565_748142_359200534_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laika the dog is &lt;em&gt;seriously&lt;/em&gt; styling in this AT-AT costume, created by Katie Mello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net&quot;&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Steve Jobs Succumbs to Alternative Medicine</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/06/jobs-succumbs-to-alt-medicine/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/06/jobs-succumbs-to-alt-medicine</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure if I believe this story, but if it is true, it is sad.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skepticblog.org/2011/10/06/steve-jobs-succumbs-to-alternative-medicine/&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs Succumbs to Alternative Medicine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most pancreatic cancers are aggressive and always terminal, but Steve was lucky (if you can call it that) and had a rare form called an islet cell neuroendocrine tumor, which is actually quite treatable with excellent survival rates — if caught soon enough. The median survival is about a decade, but it depends on how soon it’s removed surgically. Steve caught his very early, and should have expected to survive much longer than a decade. Unfortunately Steve relied on a naturopathic diet instead of early surgery. There is no evidence that diet has any effect on islet cell carcinoma. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2008/06/13/steve-jobs-life-after-the-whipple/&quot;&gt;As he dieted for nine months&lt;/a&gt;, the tumor progressed, and took him from the high end to the low end of the survival rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
