<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Josh Kerr</title>
  <link href="http://joshkerr.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joshkerr.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-10-02T11:03:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://joshkerr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Josh Kerr</name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Mou - new markdown editor for the Mac</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952713300/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952713300</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Screen Shot 2011-10-02 at 10.50.59 AM.png&quot; src=&quot;http://f.cl.ly/items/3j2o2E0V2W1T0X0q1711/Screen%20Shot%202011-10-02%20at%2010.50.59%20AM.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2011-10-02 at 10.50.59 AM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mouapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt; is described as a Markdown editor for web developers.  I displays stylized markdown code on a left pane and then the preview formatted version on the right pane.  As you write on the left, the preview is updated in realtime on the right.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve seen several editors work like this with the code on the left and preview on the right and for the most part it works.  Its nice to see your final formatted document as you write the underlying technical code.  There are however times when this doesn&amp;#8217;t work so well.  If your document has a lot of images in it, the refresh on the preview pane can be distracting as images reload from minor changes you made to the code.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mouapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt; supports syntax coloring themes which is a bonus so that you don&amp;#8217;t need to write with a white background and black text (it kills my eyes) and instead choose from a variety of sample included themes or provide your own.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The editor also supports auto-completion, incremental search and the ability to change the layout of the editor to support languages other than english.  (For example, you can transform into a vertical layout to support traditional Chinese.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to see the ability to integrate with my build system, i.e.: be able to run rake tasks or shell commands from the editor.  That way I can write an article, commit it via git and then push it to Heroku to publish live.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mou is in beta and there are a lot of great features in the pipe, so I&amp;#8217;m keeping tabs on this one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mouapp.com/&quot;&gt;Download Mou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Overview of Text Editors for Programming on the Mac</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952699410/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952699410</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not a bad overview of the different programming editors on the Mac:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://smyck.net/2011/10/02/text-editors-for-programmers-on-the-mac/&quot;&gt;Overview of Text Editors for Programming on the Mac&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last 10 years many new text editors became available for Mac OS X. Since I have tried most of them I wanted to give an overview and a brief description about each one of them. This is for developers that are looking for decent editors on the mac to get their job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets get straight to it then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Emacs / Vim&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs and Vim are really the dinosaurs of text editors for programmers. Both have a immensely rich feature set and can be extended to a degree where you can forget about the OS they are running on. Although there &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/378/&quot;&gt;is and always was a strong debate&lt;/a&gt; about which one of the two is superior, it is mostly a matter of personal taste in the end. Both have a steep learning curve and both are probably not something you want to give your web development intern on the first day at the office. However they are really powerful and they have one big advantage in common which is that they are available on a lot of operating systems and are installed by default on most of them. Whenever you log into a linux, bsd, osx or other unix machine you can be sure that vi or emacs or both are already there. On some shared web hosts you can’t even install your own packages so you are stuck with one of them. The cool thing is that you have to learn only one editor and all its specialities and you can work with it on almost any platform and on any remote machine. Since they are both really old they are known to work. They can handle big text files without crashing and for every problem you encounter there is already an extension to solve it. This is why many experienced programmers which started with more modern editors come back to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the features that very few other editors offer are: horizontal and vertical split views, whole project tab completion ( most other editors only complete words from the same file ), fundamental customization of almost every behavior of the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the features related to programming they are also powerful text editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both editors have OS X versions with a nice GUI wrapper to make them better integrated citizens, &lt;a href=&quot;http://aquamacs.org/&quot;&gt;AquaEmacs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/macvim/&quot;&gt;MacVim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really recommend reading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/&quot;&gt;blog post by Yehuda Katz&lt;/a&gt; about switching to MacVim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them are open source and free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;BBEdit / TextWrangler&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of dinosaurs of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; and the light weight version called TextWrangler come to mind. They are not as old as Emacs and Vim but BBEdit is around for 20 years! It claims to be the editor »that doesn’t suck« and it is a strong contender. However it is really focussed on text rather than programming. It has a lot of features dealing with plain text manipulation, search and replace etc. but lacks some of the features I need in my daily programming job. It has syntax highlighting, auto completion, syntax checking for a few languages and much more but in the end it always feels a little dusty compared to other editors. For example it supports SVN, CVS and Perforce but not Git in its most recent version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend BBEdit more to markup authors than to programmers but its worth checking out the website and the trial version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SubEthaEdit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how log &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subethaedit.de/index.html&quot;&gt;SubEthaEdit&lt;/a&gt; exists but its at least 6 or 7 years I’d say. The wikipedia page does not say anything about it so if one of the readers has a more accurate number let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SubEthaEdit shines in collaborative editing and most of the time that also applies more to plain text than to programming but still, its a cool feature which allows you to edit text documents via internet or local &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonjour_(software)&quot;&gt;bonjour&lt;/a&gt; connection. Other than that it is also a decent editor for programming with support for a lot of different programming languages. It is simple and does not take a whole lot of time to learn. In the end though it is also limited compared to the other more powerful editors. Non the less I think it belongs on this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Smultron&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to simple and basic text editors for programming activities you have to take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peterborgapps.com/smultron/&quot;&gt;Smultron&lt;/a&gt;. It used to be free but now its around 5$ in the Mac App Store. Still quite cheap and it features an icon you can’t miss in your dock! But seriously – its probably one of the most straight forward and simple text editors for the mac. Possibly a good entry point when you are just starting with programming and only need syntax highlighting and other basic editing features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Textmate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://macromates.com/&quot;&gt;Textmate&lt;/a&gt; was and probably still is the default text editor for many ruby developers. When the web framework Ruby on Rails first came out, the screencasts that came with it demonstrated the editing powers of Textmate so that everybody else started to use it as well. Compared to the other editors that were available at the time it was superior in almost every discipline. It was a lot better integrated into the mac environment compared to emacs or vim, offering standard shortcuts, preferences and native text controls. It supported a lot of languages and so called bundles which are a mixture of snippets, macros and other useful language specific functions like syntax validation or build system integration. It offered more comfort and flexibility than SubEthaEdit or BBEdit. It felt more productive and faster and it was easy to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I using the past tense here? Most of this still applies but Textmate did not receive a major update in years. Textmate2 became what Duke Nukem Forever was already famous for: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaporware&quot;&gt;Vaporware&lt;/a&gt;. Just recently some Textmate developer &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.macromates.com/2011/whats-next/&quot;&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; that there would be an alpha release by the end of the year but I won’t believe it until a download link shows up on their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with Textmate is mostly its lack of performance with big files, the instability of some really useful extensions and the lack of some features I have learned to love in other text editors like split views for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quit using Textmate because I used some extensions which made it crash to often and because it crashed and locked up when working with big files. Other than that it is still a great editor and its principles were copied to a lot of other editors on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even today I use it for html, xml and other markup languages because its just the fasted editor to work with in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend trying it. There is a 30-day trial version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Kod&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the people realized that TextMate2 was vaporware and no new version to fix the issues described above was in sight, alternative editors slowly began to appear. One of them is &lt;a href=&quot;http://kodapp.com/&quot;&gt;Kod&lt;/a&gt;, although it is really pretty new it is a very decent and simple to use editor for programming. Its not offering a lot of features, not like Textmate or the other more powerful editors, but still quite useful. If you don’t want to spend a few dollars for Smultron, this might be just the right editor for you. I mentioned Smultron before because it is more mature while Kod is at version 0.0.3. For additional hipness it is worth knowing that its build upon Googles V8 JS engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Kod, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; appeared as well received alternative to Textmate but compared to Kod it has the same kind of feature set as Textmate and more. It even supports Textmates color themes and language definitions which makes a migration to it quite easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It even has split views and its lighting fast. It has vertical / column selection (like Vim/Emacs/Textmate), multiple line / word select and different ways to expand the current scope of selection. Really, when I tried it the first time I was amazed how snappy it is. Like Textmate it features snippets, macros and build system integration. On the other side its highly configurable though you have to use simple config files instead of the standard OS X preference panes. I’d say its a perfect mixture of Vims configurability and Textmates editing comfort and speed. I highly recommend giving it a try if you are looking for a powerful, feature rich text editor for programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its price tag is a bit higher than others, currently 59$, but I did not have to hesitate long to support the development of this editor after using it for a couple of days in trial mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Vico&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the concepts of Vim but MacVim is not wrapping enough of Vims “awkwardness” for you then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vicoapp.com/&quot;&gt;Vico&lt;/a&gt; might be the right editor for you. Basically it uses the vim key bindings and therefore you hardly ever need a mouse to use it and it shows all the shortcuts in a native OS X menu bar. Other than split view support it is a very basic text editor for programming and features a custom scripting language to customize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Chocolat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is yet another Textmate contender but it is currently in private beta phase and its too early to really judge it as many many features are missing in it. I have to say it has the most intuitive split view implementation of all the editors mentioned here but elementary things like vertical / column selection or parenthesis / scope highlighting are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to give it a try nonetheless go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://chocolatapp.com/&quot;&gt;http://chocolatapp.com/&lt;/a&gt; and sign up for the beta or go to their irc channel on the freenode network and ask for an invite. Took me 5 minutes to get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Coda/Espresso&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools, although from different vendors, focus on the same group of people: web developers. They try to bring the entire development tool set together by bundling the functionality together that is otherwise only found in separate tools like file transfers, version control etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried them both but although they bundle together lots of features they are very limited at the same time to a certain flavor of web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still on the list as I think they will appeal to some people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.panic.com/coda/&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;http://macrabbit.com/espresso/&quot;&gt;Espresso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;skEdit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beforedawnsolutions.com/applications/skedit&quot;&gt;skEdit&lt;/a&gt; is the only editor I haven’t used personally yet so I can’t say much about it other that a colleague of mine is using it as his primary editor for quite some time now so I wanted to mention it for completeness sake. Like Coda and Espresso it is focussed on web development but its not as limited to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first editor was emacs although I only used it in a very basic way. After that I have used Textmate for a couple of years and switched briefly to MacVim for about half a year. Currently I’m using Sublime Text 2 on a daily basis for my programming work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don’t like IDE’s. There are programming languages or environments where an IDE is necessary and really superiour to text editors for programmers but I just don’t like these languages or environments either. So please don’t start a “but $IDE does all of that and more” discussion here. This is about text editors only and yes, I know … some text editors are almost like an IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I forgot to mention your favorite editor please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more elaborate list checkout &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_text_editors&quot;&gt;wikipedias comparison of text editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Statistics Prove Women are Worse at Parking</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952530453/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952530453</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the bin of stats that can in no way be accurate or based on anything scientific:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://digg.com/news/lifestyle/statistics_prove_women_are_worse_at_parking?utm_campaign=Feed%3A+http%3A%2F%2Fservices.digg.com%2F2.0%2Fstory.getTopNews%3Ftype%3Drss&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=diggapi&quot;&gt;Statistics Prove Women are Worse at Parking&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost a third of all women who failed their driving test last year came unstuck due to parallel parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://digg.com/&quot;&gt;digg&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Estimate: Amazon Kindle Fire sold at $10 loss to build share</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952530045/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952530045</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a smart move on Amazon&amp;#8217;s part.  The iPad is on fire, the only way to break in is to undercut with price and provide compelling content.  Amazon is doing both.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.electronista.com/click.phdo?i=d85c086bd58644c0e62e3caf277cd422&quot;&gt;Estimate: Amazon Kindle Fire sold at $10 loss to build share&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://photos.macnn.com/news/1109/amazonkindlefire-2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;176&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;Amazon&amp;#8217;s Kindle Fire is being sold at a loss to heat up competition with Barnes &amp;amp; Noble and Apple, IHS iSuppli estimated Friday.  Based on a list of known and expected components, it believes the seven-inch mini tablet costs $209.63 in raw parts and manufacturing, or about $10 less than its $$199 asking price.  A high-quality IPS-based LCD at $87 is a large part of that cost,  while adding the dual-core TI OMAP processor and other mainboard components pushes it up by another $70.40&lt;img src=&quot;http://amch.questionmarket.com/adsc/d887846/17/909940/adscout.php&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Electronista.com/&quot;&gt;Electronista | Gadgets for Geeks&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Video: A Look At The Fastest Chronograph Watch Ever Made</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952460871/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/10/3952460871</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/zBfTac9gozc/&quot;&gt;Video: A Look At The Fastest Chronograph Watch Ever Made&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;TAGHeuerMikrotimer2&quot; src=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/tagheuermikrotimer2.jpeg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; alt=&quot;TAGHeuerMikrotimer2&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video below shows TAG Heuer’s Mikrotimer Flying 1000 Concept watch in action. This mechanical watch times things to 1/1000th of a second – 300 times faster than a human blink. As the watch spins maniacally, it’s actually meting out 1/1000ths of a second at 500 Hz. That means the small balance wheel inside pops back and forth 3.6 million times an hour – a speed that would shatter many mechanical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not impressed? The average Rolex measures time at about 28,800 beats per hour and would probably balk at measuring time at speeds higher than 50,000 bph. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hodinkee.com/blog/2011/9/25/exclusive-hands-on-q-just-how-fast-is-tag-heuers-mikrotimer.html&quot;&gt;Hodinkee notes,&lt;/a&gt; the Mikrotimer is an “incredibly powerful caliber.” In short, this watch is a completely mechanical device that runs faster than a sports car engine and comes in a package about as big as a silver dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The watch isn’t available – it’s still a concept – but it’s a real beauty and surprisingly unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/29563992&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/zBfTac9gozc&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>I need one of these</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952311873/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952311873</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://that911.tumblr.com/post/10522600285&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrxol8Ru9s1qbcma7o1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://that911.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;That 911&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Gorgeous 911 on a cliff</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952310970/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952310970</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://that911.tumblr.com/post/10847560887&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://30.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsbkglWvH51qfzs7zo1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://that911.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;That 911&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Baby pandas need a nap (photo)</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952255740/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952255740</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/3XgK0C5-mIQ/baby-pandas-need-a-nap-photo.html&quot;&gt;Baby pandas need a nap (photo)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;RTR2RVTW&quot; src=&quot;http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/RTR2RVTW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giant panda cubs lie in a crib at Chengdu Research Base of Giant Panda Breeding in Chengdu, Sichuan province September 26, 2011. Picture taken September 26, 2011. &lt;em&gt;(REUTERS/China Daily)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net&quot;&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>PBS reporter jailed while covering protests in NYC</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952255152/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952255152</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/WcP4b_DPDCk/pbs-reporter-jailed-while-covering-occupy-wall-street-protests-in-nyc.html&quot;&gt;PBS reporter jailed while covering &amp;#8220;Occupy Wall Street&amp;#8221; protests in NYC&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;John-cropped-590x472&quot; src=&quot;http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/John-cropped-590x472.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on a story about citizen journalism at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://occupywallstreet.org&quot;&gt;Occupy Wall Street&lt;/a&gt; protests in New York for  PBS affiliate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thirteen.org/&quot;&gt;WNET Thirteen&lt;/a&gt;, reporter John Farley was arrested, along with the demonstrators whose stories he was covering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My arrest gave me a unique vantage point on the risks and rewards of citizen journalists, those non-professionals who capture stories (usually without pay) using videos and images via portable technology like a cell phone camera. Anyone, even a passerby or a police officer can be a citizen journalist. That’s its power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thirteen.org/metrofocus/news/2011/09/observations-of-a-jailed-journalist/&quot;&gt;Observations of a Jailed Journalist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Above: John Farley, kneeling, arrested while reporting on the Occupy Wall Street protest.  MetroFocus/Sam Lewis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net&quot;&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Looks: JH Audio JH16 Pro Custom In-Ear Monitor</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952245570/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952245570</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilounge.com/index.php/ipod/review/jh-audio-jh16-pro-custom-in-ear-monitor/&quot;&gt;First Looks: JH Audio JH16 Pro Custom In-Ear Monitor&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://assets.ilounge.com/images/reviews_jhaudio/jh16pro/cache/6-240x175.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;175&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If JH Audio&amp;#8217;s JH16 Pro ($1,149) looks familiar, that&amp;#8217;s because this pair of ultra high-end earphones was developed by former Ultimate Ears founder Jerry Harvey as a direct competitor to UE&amp;#8217;s top-of-line custom monitors &amp;#8211; at a lower price. JH16 Pro features eight different miniature speakers per ear: four low-end drivers, two midrange drivers, and two high-end drivers with a three-way crossover inside. Bundled with an Otter hard carrying case, a velvet…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iLounge.com&quot;&gt;iLounge | All Things iPod, iPhone, iTunes and beyond&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using Octopress & Jekyll with MarsEdit</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952242774/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952242774</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;ijFeu.png&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ijFeu.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;ijFeu.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of Octopress, the static blogging package based on Ruby and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, but because it generates static content, how can you use a blog editor like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit/&quot;&gt;Mars Edit&lt;/a&gt; with what is essentially a static blog?  Introducing &lt;a href=&quot;http://movieos.org/code/jekyll-metaweblog/&quot;&gt;Jekyll-Metaweblog&lt;/a&gt; a server that runs locally and opens up an interface to Octopress so that you can use Mars Edit to write blog entries.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Setting up Jekyll-Metaweblog wasn&amp;#8217;t straight forward, but once I got it going, it worked just fine.  I&amp;#8217;m not a Ruby guru, so my issues could be based on my inexperience with the platform.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Jekyll keeps posts in the _posts directory where Octopress puts posts in the sources/_posts directory, so you need to make sure to start the server using the correct Octopress directory.   Other than that, you should be good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Infographic: Top iPhone 5 Rumors</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952229415/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/3952229415</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raywj.com/2011/09/28/infographic-top-iphone-5-rumors/&quot;&gt;Infographic: Top iPhone 5 Rumors&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;iPhone-5-Rumors-Infographic&quot; src=&quot;http://www.raywj.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/iPhone-5-Rumors-Infographic_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; height=&quot;2841&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raywj.com&quot;&gt;Ray William Johnson&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bell & Ross Harley Is Amazing</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/bell-and-ross-harley-is-amazing/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-28T11:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/bell-and-ross-harley-is-amazing</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9Afnx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bell &amp;amp; Ross Harley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this Bell &amp;amp; Ross designed Harley Davidson.  The blue tones are sick.  This is probably a limited run bike and something that will probably cost upward of $100k.  Its a beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon Route 53 to Host Your DNS</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/amazon-route-53-to-host-your-dns/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-27T13:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/amazon-route-53-to-host-your-dns</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://f.cl.ly/items/0F022n1Y1h322b3O0m0V/Screen%20Shot%202011-09-27%20at%201.14.40%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Interstate 53&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosting your DNS is a straight forward task for most web administrators.  Use your hosts NS servers and then forget about it.  If you care about the performance and availablity of your website, you might want to think twice about where you host it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are the type of person who is running a high performanced memory cached website, then your site probably screams with performance.  DNS Resolution might be a factor that can completely slow down the performance for most of your users.  So all that horsepower means nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to host my stuff at either &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediatemple.net/&quot;&gt;Media Temple&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon or Heroku.  All three of those services provide DNS hosting, but Amazon&amp;#8217;s Route 53 in my opinion is the most capable.  The bad news is that Amazon&amp;#8217;s interface is crypting using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/developertools/Amazon-Route-53/9706686376855511&quot;&gt;perl script&lt;/a&gt; and command line to configure your zones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://interstate53.com&quot;&gt;Interstate 53&lt;/a&gt;, a website that places a front end web interface to Amazons Route 53 service.  Interstate 53 is a free service that lets you batch your DNS changes over to Amazon&amp;#8217;s Route 53 service.  So you configure your Zones, click a button and then those changes are transmitted to Amazon.  It worked well for me as I migrated my domain from another DNS provider to Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Great Loo & Placido mashup</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/great-loo/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-26T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/great-loo</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed rich soundcloud&quot;&gt;&lt;object height=&quot;81&quot; width=&quot;900&quot;&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F19922313&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; src=&quot;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F19922313&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;900&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is a great Loo &amp;amp; Placido mashup called Betty got Jacked.  (Ram Jam, Herve, C&amp;amp;C, etc..)  I love these guys.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Fantastic Dubstep Dance Routine</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/a-fantastic-dubstep-dance-routine/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-26T14:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/a-fantastic-dubstep-dance-routine</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/LXO-jKksQkM?version=3&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/LXO-jKksQkM?version=3&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure where this came from, but this guy is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dubstep in a Cereal Commercial</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/dubstep-in-a-cereal-commercial/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T14:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/dubstep-in-a-cereal-commercial</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/2YpOw8o34BM?version=3&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/2YpOw8o34BM?version=3&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m compelled to buy this cereal.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Porn Stars and Google Plus</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/porn-stars-and-google-plus/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T10:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/porn-stars-and-google-plus</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://f.cl.ly/items/090o1y460O0i0u1J4308/Screen%20Shot%202011-09-25%20at%2010.54.50%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bree Olson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received an email notification last night from Google Plus that a person named Bree Olson had added me to one of her circles.  I don&amp;#8217;t know a person named Bree, the but woman in the profile picture was attractive.  I didn&amp;#8217;t think about it again until later that night when I browsed her profile and only then did I learn that she is a professional adult film star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction was bemusement, why would she add me to her profile?  I&amp;#8217;ve never met her before, I don&amp;#8217;t work in her industry, and it is doubtful that we follow the same people.  Then I got curious.  Who is she following?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of people that Bree follows is full of people strikingly similar to me.  Regular joes who seem to be entrepreneurs and love technology.  Why is Bree adding people like me to her Google Plus circles?  Thinking about this led me to realization that here I am writing a blog post about her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bree might be leveraging Google Plus to get the word out in a very modern social sort of way.  I was so curious about the fact that she added me that I inadvertently spread word about her.  She could be a marketing genius.  Leveraging the curiosity of strangers who follow you and the fact that she is an attractive woman, she&amp;#8217;s created a very inexpensive and powerful tool to get the word out about herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porn star with marketing prowess.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Puberty</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/puberty/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T00:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/puberty</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;embed video youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/zCxxLY73nBE?version=3&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/zCxxLY73nBE?version=3&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tig Notaro Is My New Favorite Comedian</title>
    <link href="http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/tig-notaro-is-my-new-favorite-comedian/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-24T17:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://joshkerr.com/2011/09/tig-notaro-is-my-new-favorite-comedian</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;object width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; id=&quot;ep&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://i.cdn.turner.com/v5cache/TBS/cvp/teamcoco_drupal_embed.swf?context=teamcoco_embed_offsite&amp;videoId=16951&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://i.cdn.turner.com/v5cache/TBS/cvp/teamcoco_drupal_embed.swf?context=teamcoco_embed_offsite&amp;videoId=16951&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;441&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
